Inventory to the Radical right collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Radical right collection
1907-1992
90012
Hoover Institution Archives
106 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (46.5 linear feet)
The Radical right collection is comprised of pamphlets, leaflets, newspaper and serial issues, newsletters, bulletins, circulars, and other printed and near-print material issued by right-wing organizations and individuals, largely in the United States. The materials relate to anti-communist, nationalist, fundamentalist, racist, anti-Semitic, neo-Nazi, and other right-wing political movements and concerns in the United States, primarily since World War II. Also includes material relating to world government, education, mental health, fluoridation, and other issues, as well as a few letters and other manuscript materials.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990, with additional materials added subsequently.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Contents note
The Radical right collection is comprised of pamphlets, leaflets, newspaper and serial issues, newsletters, bulletins, circulars, and other printed and near-print material issued by right-wing organizations and individuals, largely in the United States. The materials relate to anti-communist, nationalist, fundamentalist, racist, anti-Semitic, neo-Nazi, and other right-wing political movements and concerns in the United States, primarily since World War II. Also includes material relating to world government, education, mental health, fluoridation, and other issues, as well as a few letters and other manuscript materials. The collection contains a number of publications by the John Birch Society, as well as ones pertaining to Gerald L. K. Smith.
The finding aid reflects the original arrangement of the materials. In many cases, these were grouped according to their place of origin. In other cases, they were organized according to title, author, or subject. The incremental materials at the end of the collection did not form part of the original collection.
Conservatism.; Right and left (Political science); United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; Anti-communist movements--United States.; Antisemitism--United States.; Christianity and politics.; Fundamentalism.; Racism--United States.; United States--Race relations.; Fascism--United States.; International organization.; Education--United States.; Mental health--United States.; Water--Fluoridation.; United States--Religion.
- Goff, Kenneth (Box-folder 1: 1-3)
- Dilling, Elizabeth (Box-folder 1: 4-6)
- Winrod, Gerald and Gordon (Box-folder 2: 1-6)
- Arizona (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
- Arkansas (Box-folder 3: 3)
- California (Box-folder 3: 4-7)
- California (Boxes 4-17)
- California (Box-folder 18: 1-4)
- Colorado (Box-folder 18: 5-8)
- Connecticut (Box-folder 19: 1-3)
- Delaware (Box-folder 19: 4)
- Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 19: 5-8)
- Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 20: 1-4)
- Florida (Box-folder 20: 5-7)
- Idaho (Box-folder 21: 1)
- Iowa (Box-folder 21: 2)
- Kansas (Box-folder 21: 3)
- Kentucky (Box-folder 21: 4)
- Maryland (Box-folder 21: 5)
- Massachusetts (Box-folder 21: 6-7)
- Michigan (Box-folder 22: 1-6)
- Mississippi (Box-folder 23: 1-4)
- Missouri (Box-folder 23: 4-5)
- Nebraska (Box-folder 24: 1)
- New Hampshire (Box-folder 24: 2)
- New Jersey (Box-folder 24: 3-6)
- New Mexico (Box-folder 24: 7)
- New York (Box-folder 24: 8)
- New York (Boxes 25-26)
- New York (Box-folder 27: 1-2)
- North Carolina (Box-folder 27: 3)
- Oklahoma (Box-folder 27: 4-5)
- Oregon (Box-folder 27: 6)
- Pennsylvania (Box-folder 28: 1-4)
- Utah (Box-folder 28: 5-6)
- Washington (state) (Box-folder 29: 1-2)
- Wisconsin (Box-folder 29: 3)
- Wyoming (Box-folder 29: 4)
- Smith, Gerald L. K. (Box-folder 29: 5-6)
- Smith, Gerald L. K. (Boxes 30-31)
- American Mercury (Box-folder 32: 1)
- Daughters of the American Revolution (Box-folder 32: 2-3)
- Flynn, John T. (Box-folder 32: 4)
- John Birch Society (Box-folder 32: 5-6)
- Liberty Lobby (Box-folder 32: 7)
- Moral Re-Armament (Box-folder 32: 8)
- Sons of the American Revolution (Box-folder 32: 9)
- Liberty Lobby (Box-folder 33: 1-5)
- Schmitz, John G. (Box-folder 33: 6)
- McBirnie, W. S. (Box-folder 34: 1-2)
- McIntire, Carl (Box-folder 34: 3)
- Religious Right (Box-folder 34: 4-6)
- Fluoridation (Box-folder 35: 1-3)
- Religious Right (Box-folder 35: 4-6)
- McBirnie, W. S. (Box-folder 35: 7)
- Religious publications (Boxes 36-37)
- Race relations (Box-folder 38: 1-6)
- Race relations (Box-folder 39: 1-3)
- Anti-Semitic literature (Box-folder 39: 4-6)
- Anti-Semitic literature (Boxes 40-42)
- United Nations and world federalism (Boxes 43-44)
- Mental health (Boxes 45-46)
- Education (Boxes 47-48)
- Religion (Boxes 49-54)
- Religion (Box-folder 55: 1-3)
- Anti-Semitic literature (Box-folder 55: 4-5)
- Anti-Semitic literature (Box-folder 56: 1-2)
- Anti-communism (Box-folder 56: 3-5)
- Anti-communism (Box-folder 57: 1-2)
- Patriotism (Box-folder 57: 3)
- Economics (Box-folder 57: 4-5)
- Economics (Box 58)
- United Nations (Box 59)
- Stickers and postcards (Box-folder 60: 1)
- Health (Box-folder 60: 2-4)
- John Birch Society (Box-folder 60: 5)
- Masons (Box-folder 60: 6)
- Sons of Liberty (Box-folder 60: 7)
- Education (Box 61)
- Education (Box-folder 62: 1-2)
- Congressional Record (Box-folder 62: 3)
- Minute Men and Women (Box-folder 62: 4-5)
- Race (Box 63)
- Race (Box-folder 64: 1-2)
- Correspondence (Box-folder 64: 3)
- Vietnam (Box-folder 64: 4)
- Fluoridation (Box-folder 64: 5)
- Co-ops (Box-folder 64: 6)
- Anti-communism (Box-folder 65: 1)
- Anti-Semitic publications (Box-folder 65: 2)
- Middle East (Box-folder 65: 3)
- B'nai B'rith (Box-folder 65: 4)
- National States Rights Party (Box-folder 65: 5)
- Religion (Box-folder 65: 6)
- Stahlhelm (Box-folder 65: 7)
- Action (Box-folder 65: 8)
- Freedom Club Bulletin (Box-folder 65: 9)
- National Message (Box-folder 65: 10)
- United States--Politics and government (Box-folder 65: 11)
- Free Enterprise (Box-folder 65: 12)
- American Statesman (Box-folder 65: 13)
- American Standard (Box-folder 65: 14)
- Citizen's Intelligence Digest (Box-folder 65: 15)
- Justice Times (Box-folder 65: 16)
- Weapons (Box-folder 66: 1-2)
- United World Federalist (Box-folder 66: 3)
- Illuminati (Box-folder 66: 4)
- Numerology/Prophecy (Box-folder 66: 5)
- Crusade for Freedom (Box-folder 66: 6)
- Space and UFOs (Box-folder 66: 7)
- Young Americans for Freedom (Box-folder 66: 8)
- We the People (Box-folder 66: 9)
- Women (Box-folder 66: 10)
- Ford Foundation (Box-folder 66: 11)
- Immigration (Box-folder 66: 12)
- Urban renewal (Box-folder 66: 13)
- New Deal (Box-folder 66: 14)
- Peace Corps (Box-folder 66: 15)
- The Arts - Literature and books (Box-folder 67: 1-4)
- The Arts - Radio (Box-folder 67: 5)
- The Arts - Museum (Box-folder 68: 1)
- The Arts - Film and television (Box-folder 68: 2)
- Walker, Edwin E. (Box-folder 68: 3)
- Canadian publications, 1950-1971 (Box-folder 68: 4-8)
- Boniecka, Krystyna, Who, What, Why: Satirical Illustrations and Text (privately printed oversize album of political cartoons), 1970 (Box 69)
- General (Box-folder 70: 1-4)
- General (Box-folder 71: 1-4)
- International
  - General (Box-folder 71: 5-6)
  - Canada (Box-folder 72: 1-6)
  - Great Britain (Box-folder 72: 7-8)
  - Rhodesia (Box-folder 72: 9)
- Alabama (Box-folder 73: 1)
- Arizona (Box-folder 73: 2)
- Arkansas (Box-folder 73: 3)
- California (Box-folder 73: 4-6)
- California (Boxes 74-79)
- California (Box-folder 80: 1-4)
- Colorado (Box-folder 80: 5-7)
- Connecticut (Box-folder 81: 1)
- Delaware (Box-folder 81: 2)
- Florida (Box-folder 81: 3-8)
- Florida (Box-folder 82: 1-4)
- Georgia (Box-folder 82: 5-6)
- Idaho (Box-folder 82: 7)
- Illinois (Box-folder 82: 8)
- Illinois (Box-folder 83: 1-5)
- Indiana (Box-folder 84: 1-3)
- Iowa (Box-folder 84: 4)
- Kansas (Box-folder 84: 5)
- Kentucky (Box-folder 84: 6)
- Louisiana (Box-folder 84: 7-9)
- Maryland (Box-folder 85: 1)
- Massachusetts (Box-folder 85: 2-6)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes numerous publications of the John Birch Society.
- Massachusetts (Box-folder 86: 1-4)
- Michigan (Box-folder 86: 5-6)
- Minnesota (Box-folder 86: 7-8)
- Mississippi (Box-folder 87: 1-3)
- Missouri (Box-folder 87: 4-7)
- Missouri (Box-folder 88: 1-3)
- Montana (Box-folder 88: 4)
- Nebraska (Box-folder 88: 5)
- Nevada (Box-folder 88: 6)
- New Hampshire (Box-folder 88: 7-10)
- New Jersey (Box-folder 89: 1-5)
- New York (Box-folder 89: 6-8)
- New York (Boxes 90-93)
- New York (Box-folder 94: 1-3)
- North Carolina (Box-folder 94: 4-7)
- North Carolina (Box-folder 95: 1-3)
- North Dakota (Box-folder 95: 4)
- Ohio (Box-folder 95: 5-6)
- Oklahoma (Box-folder 95: 7)
- Oregon (Box-folder 95: 8)
- Pennsylvania (Box-folder 96: 1-3)
- Rhode Island (Box-folder 96: 4)
- South Carolina (Box-folder 96: 5)
- South Dakota (Box-folder 96: 6)
- Tennessee (Box-folder 96: 7)
- Texas (Box-folder 96: 8-11)
- Texas (Boxes 97-98)
- Utah (Box-folder 99: 1)
- Vermont (Box-folder 99: 2)
- Virginia (Box-folder 99: 3-6)
- Washington (state) (Box-folder 99: 7)
- Washington, D.C. (Boxes 100-102)
- Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 103: 1-6)
- West Virgina (Box-folder 103: 7)
- Wisconsin (Box-folder 103: 8)
- Incremental materials
  - Americans for America (Box-folder 104: 1)
  - American Conservative Union (Box-folder 104: 2)
  - American Education Lobby (Box-folder 104: 3)
  - American Mercury, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 104: 4)
  - America's Future, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 104: 5)
  - Anglican Orthodox Church (Box-folder 104: 6)
  - Anti-communist (miscellaneous) (Box-folder 104: 7)
  - Anti-communist (Christian) (Box-folder 104: 8)
  - Anti-black literature (Box-folder 104: 9)
  - Armed Eagle (Box-folder 104: 10)
  - Augusta Courier (Box-folder 104: 11)
  - Biblical Missions (Box-folder 104: 12)
  - Christian Beacon (Box-folder 104: 13)
  - Christian Business Man's League Bulletin (Box-folder 104: 14)
  - Christian Crusade (Box-folder 105: 1)
  - Christian Crusade Weekly (Box-folder 105: 2)
  - Christian Nationalist Crusade (Box-folder 105: 3)
  - Christian Patriot (Box-folder 105: 4)
  - Christian Victory (Box-folder 105: 5)
  - Citizens Council of Greater New Orleans (Box-folder 105: 6)
  - Committee of One Million (Box-folder 105: 7)
  - Committee to Restore the Constitution (Box-folder 105: 8)
  - Common Sense (Box-folder 105: 9)
  - Conservatives (general) (Box-folder 105: 10)
  - Cross and the Flag (Box-folder 105: 11)
  - Defender (Box-folder 105: 12)
  - Fellowship News, 1971 (Box-folder 105: 13)
  - Fulbright, J. William (Box-folder 105: 14)
  - Good News Broadcaster (Box-folder 106: 1)
  - Gospel Truth (Box-folder 106: 2)
  - Human Events (Box-folder 106: 3)
  - International Christian Relief (Box-folder 106: 4)
  - Jewish Week (Box-folder 106: 5)
  - John Birch Society (Box-folder 106: 6)
  - Liberty Letter, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 106: 7)
  - Manion Forum (Box-folder 107: 1)
  - Mentor, 1971 (Box-folder 107: 2)
  - Middle East (Box-folder 107: 3)
  - Nation, 1968 (Box-folder 107: 4)
  - National Education Program (Box-folder 107: 5)
  - National Renaissance Party (Box-folder 107: 6)
  - National Socialist White People's Party (Box-folder 107: 7)
  - Pardon Me, But... (Box-folder 107: 8)
  - Plain Truth (Box-folder 107: 9)
  - Success (Box-folder 107: 10)
  - Technology Briefs (Box-folder 107: 11)
  - Texas Eagle, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 107: 12)
  - Through to Victory (Box-folder 107: 13)
  - Truth Crusader (Box-folder 107: 14)
  - Voice of the Federation (Box-folder 107: 15)
  - Woman Constitutionalist (Box-folder 107: 16)
- Miscellaneous serial issues (Box 108)